

Sunaina Saini

38/2 new gobind nagar Jalandhar,144001 Punjab/746-sector 19 near badkalmor faridabad





About Me

Highly Passionate about the Ayurveda and hence pursue a challenging career in Ayurveda and accept every opportunity, which can give me a chance to serve people along with the organization. I want to promote and provide the benefits of the Ayurveda, Diet management to the people . Experience of 2 and half years.

I am always ready to learn and improve my knowledge, working and myself. I always welcome suggestions and possess a great sense of responsibility. I am highly sincere, professional in attitude, good communication skills, excellent convincing power, optimism and team spirit are my strengths.



Education

Bachelor of Ayurvedic Medicine and Surgery

Dayanand Ayurvedic College, Jalandhar, Punjab September 2012 -april 2018

12th Standard, Biology, Chemistry, Physics

Shiv jyoti public sr.sec school ,CBSE , jalandhar Punjab April 2010 - March 2011

10th Standard

Guru nanak public sr.sec school ,jalandhar,Punjab April 2008- March 2009



Professional Training

Doctor, 1 July 2019 -30 September 2019, National Ayurvedic Research Institute for Panchkarma, Kerala, India

- All Panchakarma Procedures were learnt and Performed on Patients under guidance of Research Doctors.
- "Jalouka" and "Sira Vedan" Procedures are and learnt Performed.
- Attended OPDs for Sciatica, OA, RA, Psycho somatic disorders, digestive disorders, varicose ulcer, varicose vein and many more.



Work Experience

Doctor, 1 May 2018 –28 June 2019, Jiva Ayurvedic Hospital, Faridabad, India

- 18 Nov 2019 to till date ,in jiva ayurveda and panchkarma center ,gurgaon
- Provided OPD Consultation for IBS, Sciatica, Amala pita, Asthama, Rhinitis, kidney diseases, Blood pressure, Joint disorder, neurological disorder (Parkinson Disease, Facial paralysis etc), Piles, Fissure, fistula, constipation and Gout patients.
- Provided OPD Consultation for all above mentioned diseases.
- Attended & provided consultation for Patients in rural areas in camps organised by Jiva Ayurveda.

Trainee Doctor, 8 April 2017 – 8 April 2018 (During Morning Time), Dayanand Ayurvedic College and Hospital, Jalandhar, Punjab, India

- Assisting the senior doctor for patient's check-up and Nadi Pariksha.
- Assisting Doctors in surgery procedures like kshar sutra.
- Performing basic duties like checking the BP, sugar, etc.
- Performing patient's check-up under guidance of senior Doctors.
- Checking the reports of patients.
- Taking follow up from the nurses about regular treatment and dose of the patients.

Internship

Intern, 7 April 2017 – June 2016 (During Evening Time), metro Hospital, Jalandhar, Punjab

• Attended OPDs under guidance of Doctors

Skills

- Detailed Knowledge of all subjects of Ayurveda
- Good Command Over Handling the Medical Equipment.
- Good Leading & Communication Skills.
- Computer Skills: Computer Basics, MS Office, Internet

Compare Languages Compare Langu

- Hindi
- Punjabi
- English
- Sanskrit

Extra-Curricular Activities

- Painting & Sketching.
- Active Social worker by serving poor children and needy people around villages.
- Reading Novels, Listening Music.

e Personal Details

Birthday: September 06, 1993 Marital Status: Single Gender: Female Nationality: India